# Nhat Nguyen

## **Front End Developer**

nguyenhnhat@gmail.com (832)-800-8520 Houston,TX



Github: https://github.com/Nhatseafood

Portfolio: https://nhatseafood.github.io/New-Portfolio/

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nhat-nguyen22/

#### **Profile**

Innovative software developer, graduate of Digital Crafts, and experienced professional in the full software development lifecycle and graphic design – from concept through delivery of next-generation applications and customizable solutions. Specialized in Front End Development and creating delivering fully responsive, design oriented applications using the latest in JavaScript frameworks including Angular, React, Backbone, and iQuery.

#### Strengths Include:

- Front End Web Development with JavaScript, CSS, React, and ¡Query
- Design UI/UX
- Wide range knowledge of CMS, IDE, Source Control, languages, and emerging technologies
- Knowledge of Backend/Server side
- Strong Troubleshooting / Debugging skills
- Great Communication & Team Cooperation
- Known as self-starter and multitasker-strive to consistently exceed expectations

### **Skills & Tools**

**Languages:** HTML5, CSS3/SCSS/LESS, JavaScript, Python, SQL **Frameworks/Libraries:** React.js, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Redux

**Other:** Github, PostgreSQL, Visual Studio, Brackets, Adobe Professional Suite, Wordpress, UX and UI, Microsoft Office, Photography, Videography, Mobile Android and IOS, Mac OS X & Windows,

Bilingual Vietnamese/English

## **Experience**

### Full Time Student | Digital Crafts | FEB 2018 - MAY 20168

Completed intense vocational schooling in Front End Development by building over 20 applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and cutting edge libraries / frameworks including React.js and Backbone.js.

#### Digital Media Marketing Manager | KCI Wireless | AUG 2017 - FEB 2018

- Managed online Social Media and maintain Company website working with SEO and Google Analytics .
- Marketed for new and existing T-Mobile and MetroPCS stores
- Designed collateral for events Video Editing and Photography

## Gallery Internship | San Jacinto College | AUG 2016 - DEC 2016

- Managed correspondence to monitoring visitors
- Installed new art in the exhibits
- Designed printed collateral for gallery events

#### Graphic Designer Assistant | B7B Pipe Tools | Jan 2016 - Oct 2016

- Designed printed collateral (Brochures, advertisement, and flyers)
- Updated website and Social Media accounts
- Created Instructional Equipment videos

### Medical Assistant/Information Technologist | PMC Clinic | DEC 2012 - AUG 2016

- IT, Updated server & desktop, and Network settings.
- Triaged Patients according to clinic protocol & assessed and evaluated patient symptoms
- Documented health information in electronic health records and Fax/scans
- Delegated and supervised medical assistant duties
- Assisted medical doctors with in office procedures
- Clarify and refill prescriptions with pharmacies and medical doctors
- Educated patients about disease management and self-care
- Inputted patients data, scheduled appointments, and called patients to inform test results

## Administrative Assistant/Optician/Clerk | Scarsdale Eyecare | JAN 2010 - DEC 2012

- Optical technician
- Data Entry & inventory
- General Administrative work and organization
- Client facing Scheduled appointments
- Checked if patients are eligible for insurance
- Pre-tested and Dispensed glasses

## **Volunteer Experience**

## Art of Hope Foundation | Shriner Hospital Galveston | 2015 - 2017

- Therapeutic art activities
- Demonstrated Art Lessons
- Created Illustrations and designs
- Film and Create Video of the Art Classes

## **Education**

## **COURSE COMPLETION | MAY 2018 | DIGITAL CRAFTS HOUSTON**

- Full Stack Immersive Program
- Focus: Front End Web Development

Intensive 12 week course which focused on learning fundamentals of Front End Web Development and Back End Development that included becoming adept with professional build tools to create fully functional apps, group code reviews, and learning of various computing languages that build the web.

## ASSOCIATES PROGRAM | MAY 2010 - APRIL 2016 | SAN JACINTO COLLEGE

- Major: Associate of Applied Science in Art and Design, (Graphic Design) (AAS)
- Major: Associate of in Art (AA)
- Major: Associate of Applied Science

### Certifications

- Certificate in Full Stack Immersive Programing
- Occupational Certificate in Art and Design
- Certificate in Art and Design